Chapter 3: Know Thyself

Hannah dropped from her broomstick, her robes and hair soaking wet from condensation and low-flying clouds.

Her heart was racing. That had been the first time she'd ever been on a broomstick outside of class. She'd been so focussed on getting a good mark from Madam Hooch (and on not dying) that she hadn't really noticed that flying was fun.

The hamster floated in front of her in front of a sheer stone face in a large rock.

"You want me to follow you?" she asked. It nodded. The hamster beckoned, then floated through the rock.

Some people would find that strange or impossible, but some people hadn't had to run through a seemingly-solid masonry wall at King's Cross.

She shrugged and walked through the wall. As soon as her hand touched the stone, it turned... not quite translucent. She could still see the wall, but she could also see a tunnel behind it. It was like one of those optical illusions; depending on how you looked it at, it was either a woman with an unfashionable hat or a bowl of fruit.

Hannah shook her head and walked in.

o—o—o—o

Milo sat in the darkest corner of the dark tavern, the Hungry Hungry Hippogriff, and pulled his hood down so it covered his face, adjusting the several dozen straps, buckles, and scarves dispersed about his outfit for maximum effect. He was covered head-to-toe, save for a small area around his jaw and neck that his hood didn't cover, but he'd made sure to paint them in red whorls and twists like tattoos.

A Monk sat on the floor nearby, probably meditating about inner perfection and diamond minds and the usual trash that high-Wisdom classes got up to. A couple of dwarves were talking seriously about the goblins that had overrun their mines. The barman looked like he had a deep, dark secret that he'd take to his grave unless someone could make a moderate Diplomacy check to get it out of him.

He'd missed taverns. They'd been such a staple of his life—like shoes—that he hadn't really realized how important they were until they were gone. Not that he really ever drank, or talked to people, or ate anything that weren't his Everlasting Rations. That wasn't the important part of a tavern.

No, the important thing, the really, crucially, irreplaceable thing were the people.

Specifically, the people dressed in strange, faraway clothing sitting in dark corners.

Milo was only sitting for a few minutes when the doors slammed open. He didn't look up. That was part of the trick. Instead, he waited for the light to flicker over him, and glanced up disinterestedly—maybe too disinterestedly?—at the newcomers.

There were only three of them, and that was surprising. There were supposed to be four.

He recognized two of them, but he knew who the third was.

He hardly had time to blink before they were sitting next to him.

"Greetings, stranger," said one, a gnome.

"There are other tables," Milo said in his lowest, raspiest voice.

"True, true. But we couldn't help but notice you were watching us. And I don't recognize your clothing. Perhaps you could tell us where you're from?"

"I could. But why should I?" Milo asked, still not looking up.

The newcomer sighed. "Fine, fine. Relkin, your turn."

The one Milo didn't recognize (Relkin, presumably) spoke.

"Where are you from?" she asked.

Whoa. Milo had never been subjected to a Diplomacy check that powerful. He almost replied 'Myra! City of Light! City of Magic!' reflexively. Instead, he reminded himself that, technically, Diplomacy only worked on NPCs.

"Excuse me!" the Monk from the floor said, standing up and walking over to Milo.

"This is none of your business," Milo growled. It fell flat, though, without any Intimidate to back it up.

"No, I think I've got something to say," the Monk said angrily. "I've been waiting here for four hours for a party of adventurers to show up and help me avenge my dead master. This is my tavern. Who are you to come in here and poach my adventurers?"

Milo sighed. He hadn't expected this. But then, he'd never been on this side of the quest-giving experience before.

"Do you really want to do this?" Milo asked, still sitting down.

"If you don't leave," the Monk growled, "I'm going to kick your backside from the Clockwork Nirvana to the Ever-Changing Chaos. I'm level twelve, you know."

"Try me," Milo said.

"Haaaaaai-yeee!" the Monk shouted, charging at Milo barefisted.

"You might want to rethink that last one," Milo said.

The Monk paused. "Why?"

"You're not proficient with unarmed strikes. Minus four to attack."

"What tripe is this? Of course I'm proficient. I'm a Monk."

"Monks," Milo said in the sing-song voice of one reciting from memory, "are proficient with club, crossbow (light or heavy), dagger, handaxe, javelin, kama, nunchaku, quarterstaff, sai, shuriken, siangham, and sling," he said. "Unarmed strike is nowhere on that list."

The Monk frowned. "You're right," he said, finally. "Damn. But I don't need my fists to beat you into a bloody pulp," the Monk said, breaking a table leg off of a chair.

"For a Monk, you don't know much about Monks, do you?" Milo said. He hadn't meant for it to go this far, but the Monk left him no choice. He had to break out his secret weapon. This battle was about to get existential. "After all, is it not written, 'know thyself, and thou knowest the best way to beat in another's face?'" Milo said. "Or something like that, anyway?"

"Of course! True wisdom is in knowing yourself—thyself, whatever—and my Wisdom is through the roof! Haaaaaai-yee—"

"Ah, but you don't know yourself, do you?" Milo said, still sitting. "Because it takes a Knowledge check of ten plus the Hit Dice of a creature to recognize it, meaning it is a DC 11 check to identify a human." Milo grinned wickedly. "But it is impossible to make a check higher than ten without training. Tell me, o wise Monk, how many cross-class skill ranks have you invested in Knowledge (Local)?"

The Monk dropped the table leg and stared at his own hand in horror. "What am I?" he shrieked, looking at himself as if he'd never seen a human before—and, in a manner of speaking, he hadn't. As far as he was concerned, humans were unknown and unknowable. He broke into a cold sweat, and started to shake. Then he fled through the door, screaming at the top of his lungs.

Milo looked back at the party sitting around him.

"Sorry about that," he said. "Some people never know when to—"

"Milo?"

Milo pulled off his hood.

"Hey, guys," he said to Gerard, Zook, and... the new one. "I thought you were dead."

"We could say the same for you!" Zook said. "But you know how it is; some Wizard Wished us back to life in exchange for getting his cat familiar down from a treant, that sort of thing. You wouldn't believe how many times we tried to contact you with a Sending or bring you back with a True Resurrection—hang on. If you're here, how is..." Zook turned to look at the Bard. Then back at Milo.

Then he narrowed his eyes.

"True Seeing," he cast.

"No, I'm really me," Milo said. "It took a deus ex machina or two to get me here, but I'm here."

"So..." Gerard said slowly. "Dost this, perchance, makest thou an NPC?"

"Nope. At least, I don't think so."

"Oh, thank gods," Gerard said. "I hate doing that voice. I can never tell if it's supposed to be 'thou' or 'thee.'"

Milo glanced at the Bard, Relkin. She was hard to read behind her presumably-massive Charisma bonus and her feathered, wide-brimmed red hat, but she seemed to be deep in thought.

"Look, guys," Milo said. "I need your help."

"Of course you do," Zook grinned. "When have we ever met someone in a tavern who didn't need our help?"

"You're sure you're not an NPC?" Gerard asked.

"Pretty sure. So here's the thing: Boccob sent me back here to hunt someone down. But I've only got three days, starting about four hours ago, meaning we really have to hustle."

"That's ridiculous," Zook said. "Of course, as a divine being, he's clearly beyond our understanding," he added quickly, "but why would a god need someone found? They're practically omniscient. Boccob the Uncaring knows exactly where your target is."

"That was my thinking too," Milo said. "I think he doesn't actually want her found. I think he wants to get me and her in the same room together, sixty-eight hours from now. I already tried locating her with magic, but she seems to be under the effects of a Nondetection spell or something similar. She's a witch named Bellatrix—"

"Myra," Relkin interjected. "City of Light! City of Magic!" she added half-heartedly.

"Oh. Is she not hiding, then?"

"Don't know. This is the first I've heard about her. But we've been getting foreshadowing about shady goings-on in Myra (CityofLight!CityofMagic!) for ages now. But, since that Wizard who brought these guys back to life was on the other side of the continent, it's taken us a while to get back. And there were all these sidequests to do, MacGuffins to find, mysteries to solve, dungeons to raid... up until last week, when there was nothing. The quests dried up, and suddenly we were moving like lightning. Until now. You're the first notable NPC we've met in a week. Coincidence? I think not."

"I'm not an NPC," Milo bristled. "But your reasoning seems sound. Besides, there's... someone else I have to see in the city."

"Just one question," Relkin said. "What the hells is a witch?"

o—o—o—o

Hannah crept deeper into the cave. She wasn't exactly sneaking or anything, but it seemed almost impossible to walk into a mysterious hidden cave without creeping. She found herself wishing she'd brought a torch; she had her wand, of course, but didn't dare use it. Stupid underage magic rules.

Still, if only she could see...

As soon as she thought it, the hamster on her shoulder disappeared, and the walls and floor of the cave, just barely visible before, were highlighted in a web of silvery lines.

"Cool," she whispered, walking more confidently now.

The cave opened up into a little square room hewn out of the rock and earth, supported in places by neatly-sawn timber beams and posts. There was a wooden table in the centre of the room, an overstuffed armchair in the corner, and the walls were all lined with shelves and drawers.

"Hello." It was Milo's voice. Hannah whipped around, but couldn't see him. Of course, she couldn't see much of anything in the darkness beyond the silvery outlines. "If you're hearing this, it means your Christmas present detected you were thinking I was dead. If this is a ploy and I'm planning a—" the voice cut out briefly, then picked up again with a slightly different cadence. It was a little like listening to a poorly dubbed Japanese cartoon. "—daring comeback, I'll leave a note on that table explaining everything. However, failing that, I've made certain contingency plans. Presumably, my death means the world—" the voice cut out again. Hannah frantically ran her hands over the table, trying to find Milo's note. "—the world has fallen to You-Know-Who. Or a housecat got in a lucky hit. This shelter contains everything you need to run an—" there was another pause, longer this time. "—Dammit, I need to speak more concisely. Twenty-five words is a ridiculously short message to leave, and I've only got one more Magic Mouth—"

There was no note. Still, that didn't mean anything, right? It didn't mean he was dead. It just meant, as he'd said, that she thought he was dead. Which was absolutely jumping to conclusions. Right.

He was probably enjoying his summer in... well, in wherever it was he went during the summer. She wondered where that was.

"—Come on, 'twenty-five' is a compound modifier, not two words! Anyway. This shelter contains everything that Cog could make, or that I could mail—" Another pause. "Or that I could mail-order that might be necessary for whatever the current emergency situation is. There are spare wands, non-perishables, money, grappling—" Another pause. "—Argh. You get the idea. Look around. There's also an armchair in the corner and a set of wizard chess so you can talk about—the weather and get your spells back. There's also some copies, sans illustrations, of some school textbooks that I thought might be useful. The hamster—knows where to find the other twelve identical shelters I built. I know I said your Christmas present was going to be fun rather than—rather than useful, but I couldn't resist. You probably also noticed that the hamster can project images of rooms when you're in the dark, but—it only works in places that someone who's been within 60 feet of the pin has seen, and only you can see the image." There was a pause. A real one, as if Milo was hesitating before continuing, not one of the weird ones. "If—you're not running for your life, and he didn't go down fighting or suffer existential failure, please take care of my rat, will you? Happy—Christmas, Hannah Abbot."

And then there was silence.

o—o—o—o

"So, what's the plan?" Zook asked.

Milo slid a piece of paper across the table. "We'll need everything on that list, but I don't have any money." He'd had to tear the sheet out of Thamior's spellbook just to make the shopping list.

Zook scanned the sheet.

"Why do we need five tower shields?" he asked.

"I guess it's only four since Wellby's not here," Milo said. "Where is he, by the way?"

"He wasn't with us when we were resurrected," Gerard said. "We assumed at first that he chose to stay in the afterlife, but we've since heard that he might be in Myra, City of Light! City of Magic! We don't know why, though. He's not responding to our messages."

Milo and Relkin exchanged a look.

"Bellatrix has access to a... permanent-duration at-will domination spell with an implausibly-high DC," Milo said. "She got him."

"How do you know that?" Zook asked.

"She didn't kill him when she killed you two," Relkin said. "He was also the last one alive. She's from another plane, so she'd need a local guide. Rogues have infamously poor Will saves. He's also in the same city she is, and he's not returning your messages. He would if he was able."

"So. All we need now is four fast horses to get to the city," Milo said. He could take another Phantom Steed, but he wanted to conserve his magic as much as possible. He wasn't really certain what to expect, and wanted to be prepared for anything. And besides, he couldn't fit all four of them on the back of a single horse, magical or not.

"Horses won't get you there in time," Relkin said. "Fortunately, I have better."

o—o—o—o

Hannah found a pile of curious foot-long iron rods in one of the shelves labelled, in that same weird silvery outline, a 'sunrod—glows when struck.' She wondered what struck meant in this case. Was it in the sense of how someone might strike a match? Or did she have to kick it or something? Or maybe the sunrods had to engage in collective bargaining and refuse services as a bargaining ploy? She knew Milo's definition of certain words differed, somewhat, from the norm.

She decided to go with the first option, and struck one, like a giant match, against the wooden table. As soon as she did, the tip—which turned out to be made of gold—began to glow brightly, illuminating the room. Wherever the light touched, the silvery lines disappeared.

She rooted around in the drawers until she produced some blank paper and a quill, and placed them on the table. Then she looked at the hamster pointedly.

"Right," she said. "I think you'd best draw where the rest of these little hideaways are."

o—o—o—o

It was a chaotic, gaudy mess in the shape of a sailing ship—sans sails. The hull and deck were carved and painted in a variety of seemingly-random swirly patterns and shapes. On the side, painted in bright silver, was its name: S.S. ROLL FOR INITIATIVE.

A complicated mechanism resembling a waterwheel was mounted on the rear, spinning like a Fighter with Combat Reflexes, Improved Trip, and a spiked chain surrounded by kobolds who had never read page 137 of the PHB.

And the whole thing moved like Greased lightning.

"What is this monstrosity?" Milo shouted over the wind as they shot down the river.

"It's a boat," Relkin said.

"What... what makes it go?"

"Zombies," Relkin said with aplomb, steering the ship down the winding river.

Milo choked slightly. "Zombies?"

"And a gaggle of skeletons. There's a couple of zombie crocodiles in the hold turning a crank," Relkin said. "Good strength-to-HD ratio, and the river is just lousy with them. Some of the more complicated machinery is actually haunted, with a couple of skeleton squirrels Hauntshifted in as poltergeists. The ballistae mounted on the sides self-load the same way, but someone has to actually aim and fire them. I'm working on that bit, still."

Milo frowned. Theoretically, an undead poltergeist could make simple machinery move, like making a clock run backwards. But he'd never heard of anyone... weaponising it. The rule was only there to add a certain flavour to haunted houses.

"How could you justify spending so much of your wealth-by-level on a method of transportation?" Milo asked. "Everyone knows that not even a high overland speed lets you break the one-encounter-per-trip rule."

Theoretically, there were supposed to be random encounters with hostile monsters every so often while travelling, but nobody, not even the monsters themselves, had time for that. Random encounters were a waste of time for all involved parties. However, since they couldn't have travel through dangerous wildernesses just be safe, a compromise of sorts was reached: any trip through the wild, of any length, would have exactly one random encounter. It was a scientifically-proven fact.

"True," Relkin said. "But I didn't actually spend anything on this. I made it."

"Oh, please," Milo said. "You don't expect me to believe you put that many ranks into Craft (Shipbuilding), Knowledge (Architecture and Engineering), and, for that matter, Profession (Sailor)? Is this like that time you decided I should have a higher Charisma than Constitution?"

"I don't know what you're talking about," Relkin said woodenly. "I had nothing to do with that decision. And besides," she added in a more normal tone, "I didn't waste any ranks in any of those skills."

"Then how...?"

"Bardic Knack and Jack-of-all-Trades, combined with some lucky ability rolls. I have a high skill bonus in every skill. You see the art on the deck?"

"It's... hard to miss."

"Well, artistic crafts like Craft (Woodcarving) and (Abstract Art) let you make high-value works of art from low-cost raw materials, so when I have some free time, I throw on another coat of paint. At last count, there's fifteen thousand gp in masterwork paintings layered on top of each other on this boat for when I decide to sell it when I learn Teleport. That number is only going up."

"Impressive. I once brewed a magical potion in a completely different magic system from ours without a feat," Milo said.

"You must be very proud. I once buffed a donkey to the point where it killed a hill giant without taking any damage."

"Only a hill giant? Hmph. I foiled the plans of an immortal, evil mastermind with a first-level spell."

"I can add my Charisma to attack," the Bard said. "Three times. And once to damage."

"I made a headband that gave me seven feats using only a second-level spell."

"Mirror Move? Way ahead of you." Relkin fished an amulet out from her red coat and dangled it in front of Milo. "In a few levels I'll get access to the whole Sorcerer/Wizard spell list."

"Oooh, so you'll be almost as good at magic as a Sorcerer? I tremble at the thought. In seven levels I'll get access to the whole Cleric spell list and the Wizard list—without sacrificing any caster levels."

"I can cast spells without preparing them."

"So can I," Milo grinned. "And I'm a Wizard."

"Well, I get better saves and more hit points per level than you."

"Bah! If it comes down to your hit points, you've already lost."

"I can craft any item at one-third price!'

"I can craft magic items at one-sixtieth of their value!"

"Lot of good you did with it. You haven't got a single magic item on you. In fact, aside from that spellbook and those black robes, you don't have anything."

"I have a mother, and that's more than you can say."

Relkin cocked her head sideways slightly and looked at Milo. "So?" she asked.

"If you have to ask—" Milo narrowed his eyes, staring at the reflection of the setting sun in the water ahead. "That's not a reflection."

"You see it, too?" Relkin asked. She reached behind him and pulled on a rope, ringing an alarm bell deep within the ship. She slammed forward a lever marked 'REVERSE' and drew a weird, crystalline sword from her hip.

Milo dived for cover behind the gunwale as a cloud of superheated steam buffeted the ship. His Reflex save was garbage; had he been caught in that blast he would have died for certain. Even if he'd made his save there would have been nothing left but a pair of smoking boots. Relkin stood behind the wheel looking unharmed; clearly, she'd managed to munchkin her way into getting Evasion somehow.

There was a roar that Milo's ears didn't so much hear as suffer through as the monster surfaced.

Its wide, streamlined shell was covered in jagged, silvery protrusions that caused the light to dance in a beautiful, mesmerizing way that looked a little like the reflection of light on the water. A long, snakelike neck reached out of the water, ending in a scaled, crested head and a mouth lined with several dozen rows of razor-sharp teeth; still steaming from the breath attack earlier.

The Dragon Turtle slammed into the Roll for Initiative, shattering the mermaid figurehead and sending splinters flying across the deck.

Its sea-green eyes scanned the deck and looked straight at Milo. Then it opened its mouth again, ready to send forth another blast of superhot steam.

"Oh, crap."

Chapter 8: Boss Room

"Was that the signal?" Reginald whispered.

"No," Regina whispered back, peering through her spyglass. "It was just something from the Mage's Guild." The battle, or whatever was happening, at the Mage's Guild had largely died down, but every now and then a lightning bolt or wave of sick-looking fog flew out of an open window. Most of the upper storeys were on fire, and several load-bearing-looking walls lay in ruins. Knowing magic, though, the carnage would likely only take a few minutes to clear up, or, more likely, several months of work by poorly paid servants while the resident Wizards took the opportunity to do 'critical spell research' on a sunny island someplace.

"Why are we whispering?" Reginald asked. "We're halfway across the city from the action."

"How should I know?" Regina asked. "You started it."

"Was that it?"

"No, that was just the sun."

"How about—"

"No."

o—o—o—o

Lkoturo the Grand Vizier hadn't been wrong.

The aged darkwood doors didn't look particularly formidable. Tall, dark, and expensive, just like their previous owner. Sure, darkwood was pretty tough stuff, but it couldn't hold a candle even to steel, and the doors were clearly only using it because it looked pretty.

Nevertheless, they were nigh-indestructible. The grain was so laced with defensive spells and traps that Milo was almost surprised it didn't glow.

"I don't have enough Dispel Magics to put a dent in this door," Relkin said, almost in awe.

"All the Wizards in the world wouldn't have enough," Milo said. It was an exaggeration, but not by as much as one might hope.

"What's the big deal? I've never seen a door that stood up to this little adamantine master key," Gerard said, patting his sheathed greatsword.

"See those little light flecks in the wood?" Milo asked. "There's one there near the bottom, and another by the knocker."

"Sure," Gerard shrugged. "What are those, traps? A simple matter to avoid them."

"No," Milo said. "Those are the only areas not stained by the amber used to make a Sepia Snake Sigil."

"Well, actually," Relkin corrected, "it's an unrelated spell heavily based off of Sepia Snake Sigil that triggers off of the door opening, and probably damage, but not by reading-"

"Yes, yes," Milo said irritably. "Lies-to-Fighters, remember?"

"I think I can make a Reflex save," Gerard said defensively. "I have a Cloak of Protection."

"But can you make five thousand, six-hundred and seventy-seven?" Milo asked. "Besides, that's not even including the Symbol of Insanity scrawled in the doorjamb, there. Of course, it's only potent when clearly visible, and as such poses no threat—as long as the door remains closed."

"Hmm," Gerard said, backing away carefully from the door. "I begin to see your point."

"So..." Zook said. "If we can't get in through the door, what do we do?"

"Gerard?" Milo said. "Break that window."

Gerard shrugged and effortless kicked the window clean off of its pane, letting the rays of early-morning light shine in through the gap. How long did they have until Boccob's three days were up? Minutes? Seconds?

"I don't know what you have planned," Zook said, "but I am not climbing out the window on the top floor of a fifteen-storey palace."

"You'll see," Milo said. "But before we do this, we need to be absolutely clear on something. Everybody listening?"

Relkin, Zook, and Gerard shrugged, nodded, and grunted, respectively.

"In all likelihood, Bellatrix Lestrange is through this door," Milo said.

Gerard cracked his knuckles meaningfully.

"Two of you have seen her fight once before, and she killed both of you without breaking a sweat. You had what, two, three rounds before you went down? Right. I've been fighting people like her back in the other world for over a year now, and it's not like combat here. It's messy and chaotic and confused and if they so much as touch you with their magic, you're dead. No ifs, ands, buts, or saving throws."

"We understand," Relkin said impatiently.

"No," Milo said. "You don't. If we go in there, you will have no idea what you're dealing with. She doesn't have hit points. She doesn't have an armour class. She doesn't even really have a place in the initiative order. You're all used to encounters that are carefully tailored to your respective levels and abilities to be a balanced, fair challenge that might prove difficult but is nonetheless designed for you to win in under a minute." Milo paused to let that sink in. "Bellatrix won't be like that. She comes from a different world with different rules and we won't be able to defeat her unless we recognize that."

"We'll be careful," Gerard said.

"You'll be more than that," Milo said seriously. "You'll stay out of it. I'll handle Bellatrix."

"What?" Relkin said. "That's crazy! You'll fight the BBEG? Alone? Look at you! No magic items. No familiar. No decent spells. Basically no hit points. You don't stand a chance."

"Hit points won't matter in this fight," Milo said. "And I won't be able to both fight her and worry about you."

"So, what do you want us to do?" Zook said. "Just sit around here and polish our Holy Symbols? You can't seriously expect us to agree to this."

"No," Milo said. "She'll probably have a trick up her sleeve. An ace in the hole. While I'm fighting her, I need you three to cover my back against surprises. I don't know about you guys, but I don't believe for a second that that Lorcko guy, or whatever his name was, told us everything."

"We'll see," Relkin said. "But if it's going to be as tumultuous as you're describing, the situation may change in ways you can't predict. I can't promise I might not step in if it comes to that."

Zook nodded. "Same here."

"Besides," Gerard said. "We can't let you get all the XP."

Milo nodded. That was probably the best he was going to be able to get out of them. "Dancing Lights." Four pinpoints of red light appeared floating over his head. "All right, gentlemen. And lady. Shields up."

With a wave of his hand, the lights flew out of the window.

There would be no backing out now.

o—o—o—o

"Was that it?"

"Yeah," Regina said, lowering the spyglass. "Yeah, I think that was it."

"Well," Reginald said. "Here goes."

He reached down and, without further drama, released the catch. The catapult kicked into the air as it released the enormous stored energy in its wound sinew springs.

From her vantage point, Regina couldn't see the eleven other teams positioned throughout the city. But she didn't need to—she could see their effects.

o—o—o—o

It is a common misconception that catapults throw ponderous projectiles in high, slow arcs with little finesse or accuracy. Your standard siege catapult is capable of launching a seventy-five kilogram projectile well over three hundred meters. Catapults are more than capable of stripping battlements from city walls, and could seriously damage or destroy even hardened military fortifications with sustained fire. Over the centuries, advancements in catapult technology necessitated thicker, stronger walls designed with, and to defend against, the (often literally) bleeding edge of military engineering and technology.

Of course, none of that actually mattered here. Force, mass, and acceleration were all merely flavour text, but 6d6 damage was 6d6 damage no matter now you looked at it, especially when a six inch masonry wall only has 45 hit points per 10 square feet.

Mortar dust rained over their heads as the exterior wall suddenly buckled inwards. A handful of bricks were knocked loose, but the wall held.

A moment later, the wall exploded inwards as another half-dozen head-sized stones collided with the civilian architecture almost simultaneously.

A chunk of baroque masonry slammed into Milo's tower shield, which was, through a strange quirk in the rules, the next best thing to indestructible.

Despite himself, Milo chuckled quietly in the dust. More like baroque-en masonry...

The dust cleared.

Lkoturo's door was still standing, apparently unscathed.

The wall around it, however, had gone to metamorphic heaven.

In the remains of what had once been a grandiose office, a woman sat behind a shattered desk, holding a steaming bone china teacup. Her hair was dark and wild beneath the white dust, and she wore a black dress with enough folds, lace, and patterns that Milo didn't doubt there were multiple places one could hide a knife without it showing. Over the dress, she had a leather bag slung over her shoulder.

"Ah," she said, setting down the cracked cup on the crooked table."Heroes." She stood up, idly brushing dust from her clothes. "I hadn't planned on killing any of you lot today, but eh," she shrugged, causing powdered stone to rain from her. "If life gives you lemons..."

Milo dropped his tower shield. He wasn't going to risk a fifty percent spell failure chance on the untested assumption that his exploit would work against her.

"Lestrange," he said, shaking his hands free of his sleeves. "You—"

"Will never get away with it?" Bellatrix asked.

"No, you—"

"Are going down? For justice? The good of mankind? For," she gestured vaguely, "Chester? Lucy?" She frowned. "Have I killed any Lucys lately?" she said, apparently to herself.

"What? No, you—"

"Fiend?" she suggested. "Ooh, how about, 'you may think you've won, but the real punishment will be your own conscience?' It's been years since I've heard that one."

"You don't belong in this world," Milo said.

"Pfft. I was hoping for something new. What did I do, kill your cat or mommy or something? Just once I'd like to kill a hero not out for vengeance. Or 'justice,' for that matter." she made little quotation marks in the air with her fingers. "How about... boredom. Hardly anybody tries to kill me out of boredom. Ooh, or for meringues. Nobody's tried that. And believe me, my meringues are to die for." She frowned. "No, that's my sister's meringues. Mine tended to scream, which always put people off for some reason." Bellatrix stared at Milo, as if noticing him for the first time. "So, what's your deal?"

"I was killed by a book and my god returned me to life to find you."

"Wow, that is new. Avada kedavra." She said it like one might say 'Well, whatever,' or, 'That's public transit for you.' She didn't quick-draw like a gunslinger, or scream like a barbarian, or even shrug. She just said it, as if the words were ordinary conversation. Maybe to her, they were.

But Milo had been ready for it—literally. His Readied spell sprung into action almost before he was really aware that the combat had started.

"Summon Skeletal Troll." A great skeleton of a lanky beast with far too much arm and too little leg appeared directly in the path of the Unforgivable Curse, which burst harmlessly against its chest.

Bellatrix cocked her head sideways. It was a curiously bird-like gesture. Her wand, however, remained perfectly still. "I see you know a thing or two."

Milo shrugged. "You're not the first Death Eater I've fought." This was good. Undead were immune to, near as Milo could tell, all three of the Unforgivable Curses. Death Eaters never seemed to cast anything else, so as long as he could keep the Troll between him and Bellatrix, he'd have this.

Bellatrix grinned. It was a terrifying expression in that it was absolutely genuine. She was, if his ranks in Sense Motive were to be believed, completely thrilled to be fighting.

"Fascinating!" she said. "I'll have to have somebody here magic the answer to that little riddle out of your corpse," she said. "But first—Diffindo!" Bellatrix swiped her wand in a horizontal arc in front of her.

At first, nothing seemed to happen. A moment later, the skeleton seemed to waver slightly, as if unsteady. Then it collapsed, the top half of its skull sliding from its head, severed by a single, unimaginably sharp cut. The skeleton vanished before it hit the ground.

"Oh," Milo said. "Crap."

After that whole lecture to his party, he couldn't believe he'd simply assumed that Bellatrix Lestrange—Bellatrix Lestrange—would simply follow the patterns set by other Death Eaters. The witches and wizards of magical Britain had been terrified of this woman, and with good reason—not only was she, from what he'd heard, completely psychotic, but she evidently possessed a far more frightening trait: she could change her tactics.

"Glitterdust!" A familiar burst of golden light flew out of Milo's outstretched hand at the witch.

"Scourgify," Bellatrix cast casually, wiping the dust away. Oh, Hell... Milo knew what was coming next, and dived behind a convenient pile of rubble. "Oppugno!" she cast in the same breath.

I guess she and Draco are blood, after all...

Milo's golden dust formed into a wispy line and flew back at him, avoiding the rubble with ease. For once, he was glad that he no longer had his spell-enhancing equipment, as its lack was the only reason he as able to evade the spell.

He was dimly aware of the noise of fighting coming from the hallway outside, and heard Zook's voice shout out "Don't kill them! They don't know what they're doing!"

Milo resolved to stop messing around and aim for her obvious weak spot. He popped out over the rubble and targeted her wand.

"Shatter!"

Bellatrix's wand exploded in her hand, sending splinters flying across the room. The witch blinked in surprise at her bleeding hand.

"My mother gave me that wand," she said in a hushed voice.

Milo heaved a sigh of relief. He'd half-expected her to have some devious countermeasure. Now, it would only be a simple matter of subduing her, maybe with Evard's Black Tentacles, or perhaps a summoned monster.

Abruptly, she smiled. "Oh, no, I forgot. That was this wand," she said, producing a seemingly-identical wand from behind her back. With a shrug, she tossed it away behind her back. "Or maybe this one," she said, drawing yet another from up her sleeve. "With the Geminio Charm, it's easy to lose track. Incarcerous."

Dozens of ropes sprung out of the oak wall behind Milo, grabbing him by the arms, legs, and neck and pinning him to the wall. He struggled, but it was futile. What kind of self-respecting Wizard would put ranks in Escape Artist, anyway?

Bellatrix clapped her hands together. "Bravo!" she said, apparently genuinely thrilled. "That was, what, twenty, thirty seconds? That's more entertainment than I get out of most. You should be proud! I'd cut you down for an encore performance, but, well, I think I'll just kill you instead."

Behind Bellatrix, Milo saw Relkin stalking silently across the room, sword in hand. She gave him a wink.

Milo's mind raced. He had to keep Bellatrix talking.

"I wouldn't kill me, if I were you," he said.

"Of course!" Bellatrix said. "I wouldn't kill me if I were me, either. It goes without saying, really. Flagrate." Milo smelled faint wood smoke as the tip of her wand lit up into a bright white ember.

"No, I mean, really," Milo stammered. Bellatrix playfully traced her wand against the wood panelling Milo was pinned against, leaving a scored black mark. "Aren't you the least bit curious about how I previously encountered Death Eaters?"

"Honestly? Not really," Bellatrix said, hovering her smoking wand tip just in front of Milo's left eye.

Just as Relkin approached within the reach of her weapon, Bellatrix snapped her fingers. A shadowy figure dropped silently from the ceiling, swords poised to strike.

Before Milo could cry out, the stranger stranger's weapons flashed. Relkin whirled about and deftly parried the first with her crystal sword, but was a hair too slow to catch the second. She screamed and clutched at her shoulder, blood leaking between her fingers.

"Where was I?" Bellatrix asked. "Oh, of course." Slowly, deliberately, she moved her smoking wand towards his eye.

Milo wished he could say that he stared her down coolly, but, in truth, he began to crack. He didn't want to die again, or for his sister to die. He was more terrified of this strange, quicksilver witch than he had been of almost anyone before—perhaps more so, even, than of Tom Riddle.

The wand was so close that he could feel his face starting to burn.

I don't want to die, I don't want to die, I don't want to die, I DON'T WANT TO DIE.

"What was that?" Bellatrix asked sweetly.

"I don't want to die!" Milo screamed. He struggled against the ropes and the wooden wall in vain.

Wait.

The wooden wall.

Milo slammed his palm against the oak behind him. Abruptly he began to slide as the wall collapsed into dozens upon dozens of narrow wooden quarterstaves, just like he had with the ship's mast. It wasn't even magic; anyone could do it. He collided with Bellatrix's shins, and they both tumbled to the ground, sliding across the floor in a great wave of walking sticks.

"And people say Craft is underpowered!" Milo said, climbing to his feet. He'd stopped sliding just next to the huge open dropoff where the external wall had once been.

Milo looked at the small figure fighting Relkin. At the hooded cloak, the twin swords...

"Wellby?"

"Avada Kedavra!" A green bolt of light grazed Milo's face, colliding with the wall behind him. Milo whirled around, Readying another Summon Undead III. He was fighting too defensively, he knew, but what else was he going to do? If he tried to take her out and missed, he'd be wide open to a Killing Curse.

Bellatrix was back on her feet, yet another wand in her hand. Her previous one was lying among the pile of wooden weaponry, still smoking.

"Oh, you're fun," she laughed. "Nobody from this mad, fake world has put up even half the fight you have! Look—Expecto Patronum!" A wispy, translucent white snake slithered out of her wand, and wrapped itself around her legs. "I'm having a great time!"

"I know the feeling," Milo muttered. He'd fought whole rooms full of Death Eaters before with less difficulty than this. Of course, he'd had Mordenkainen then, and his belt full of tricks, but his primary weapon had always been his spells. Bellatrix seemed to have an answer to all of them—and she could cast much, much faster than he could.

"Avada Kedavra!"

"Summon Zombie Kobolds," Milo cast, aiming for quantity over quality. Four small, rotting reptilian creatures appeared in a line between him and Bellatrix. The Killing Curse burst harmlessly against the first one's decaying torso, and the four disgusting little creatures rushed the witch. With her distracted, Milo glanced at Relkin, who was losing ground—and hit points—to Wellby's superior, non-caster combat abilities. She hadn't seemed to have clued in to his identity, yet—maybe because, technically, she hadn't actually met him before.

"Benign Transposition," he muttered. Suddenly, he was facing his old party mate, and Relkin was standing by the open wall. "Look, Wellby—" Milo was interrupted by Wellby slashing him across the chest with one of his blades. "Gods dammit," Milo cursed. Not for the last time, he wished he'd taken the penalty to Charisma rather than Constitution. "Fine, be that way. Protection from Good."

Wellby blinked his eyes repeatedly, as if he'd just woken up from a long dream.

"Milo?" he asked.

"Later," Milo said. "We'll deal with Lestrange first."

Wellby's eyes hardened. "Yes," he said. "Yes, we will."

The three of them and the two kobolds still standing surrounded Bellatrix.

"Well," she laughed. "Win some, lose some."

Chapter 15: The Tour Guide

It was a small, dark, room with walls of bare stone. From somewhere behind him, Milo could hear an irregular drip... drip-drip... ... ... drip... drip-drip-drip that was wreaking havoc on his concentration. A single light, simultaneously too bright to be comfortable and too dim to illuminate the room, hung above him, flickering occasionally. Milo himself sat in an uncomfortable, nondescript chair behind a simple metal table across from Bones, Shacklebolt, Peasegood, and a couple of unknown mooks.

It was the sort of room that governments throughout time and across dimensions have, somewhere, but rarely show to school tour groups. This one was labelled 'Interview Room H.'

"What do you know about the escaped fugitive, Sirius Black?" Amelia Bones asked him. The two witches that had followed Shacklebolt into the compartment earlier stood by the door with unreadable expressions on their faces. Shacklebolt himself, however, was conspicuously absent. Drip... drip...

Milo shrugged. "That his cousin, Ridiculous Black, is way more fun at parties." Drip... dripdrip-drip-DRIP... drip.

"He's lying," said Arnold Peasegood, the Obliviator. Drip... ... drip... Milo hadn't seen either of these two since he'd sold them his flawed Amulets of Protection.

"Yes, I know he's lying," Bones snapped. "Anyone can tell he's lying." She turned back to Milo. "This will be much easier if you just tell us what you know. It's for your own safety."

"I know I've never been told anything was 'for my own safety' by an authority figure who was completely on the up-and-up," Milo said. Drip-drip... DRIP. "And I know that the Amulets you two are wearing—"

"Brinks, Wu," Bones snapped. "Leave." If the two witches were surprised by the order, they didn't show it. They filed out without a word. She aimed her wand at the closed door. "Colloportus," she muttered, then put the wand away again.

"Things are really falling apart around here, aren't they?" Milo asked. Drip... DRIP-drip. "People escaping from Azkaban left, right, and centre, Hogwarts governors being murdered in their homes, supposedly memory-wiped Muggles being a little too persistent..."

"How do you know about that?" Peasegood snapped. He glanced at Bones, who cocked an eyebrow. "The situation is completely under control," he said, loosening his tie slightly. "A handful of Obliviated Muggles seemed to have relapsed last year. It's happened before."

"We'll discuss this later," Bones said firmly, before looking back at Milo. "What's this about our amulets?"

"They're flawed," Milo explained. "You-Know-Who will be able to Imperius you even if you're wearing them. I'm sorry. I'll give you a... partial refund. Say, fifteen percent?"

"Ridiculous," Peasegood said. "Every amulet has been thoroughly tested against all manner of threats, up to and including the Imperius Curse. They've performed flawlessly."

Bones narrowed her eyes. Drip-drop-drip-drip... ... ... DRIP. "The real question," she said slowly, "is what your vested interest is in having us remove them."

"What?" Milo hadn't seen this coming at all. "No, I was just trying to warn—"

"Is it so that Sirius Black and his followers will be able to seize control of the Ministry?" Bones pressed.

"That's ridiculous. You people don't even get feats, much less Leadership. There's no way he could have followers—"

"Did you facilitate Sirius's escape from Azkaban?"

"I barely even knew Azkaban existed until—" Milo cut himself off before he could say 'until Sirius told me.' "Until the story of Sirius's escape broke."

"What do you know about the disappearance of Gilderoy Lockhart?"

Drip... drip...

"Clocktart? What's he got to do with this?"

"Did Sirius Black kill Lockhart?"

Drip... drip...

"No!"

DRIP.

Everybody froze for a second, and Milo realized he'd made a mistake.

"And what makes you so sure?" Bones asked slowly. "What do you know, Milo?"

"I misspoke," Milo rushed. "I thought you said 'Do you know if Sirius Black killed Lockhart,' and I said, 'No,' as in, 'No, I don't know—'"

"Stop stalling!" Bones slammed her fist down on the table, leaving a small dent in the cheap metal. "We know you can do things no-one else can. Nobody's ever broken out of Azkaban—just like how nobody's ever blocked an Unforgivable Curse before, much less Charmed a piece of cheap jewelry to do it for them."

The horrible steel chair Milo sat in was committing war crimes on his lower back. "I didn't fare too well against the Dementor you sent to the Hogwarts Express—real nice, by the way, turning one of those things loose on a train full of children—so I don't see how I could have walked into Azkaban and broken Black out." He raised his hands up above the table's surface to stretch in an attempt to work out the kinks in his back.

"Incarcerous!" Bones shouted.

Milo hadn't even seen Bones draw her wand, but thick ropes shot out of it, pinning Milo against the wall. He was uncomfortably reminded of the time, only a few days ago, when Bellatrix had him in a similar position.

"Boccob Uncaring!" Milo cursed, fighting against the ropes. "I was just trying to stretch!"

"We've tried to be polite so far," Bones said. "But you must realize we can get the truth out of you, one way or another, don't you?"

Milo struggled slightly, but it was to no avail. "I'm shrugging right now," he said. "I know you can't tell, on account of all the freaking ropes, but that was a shrug. If you could make me, you would have already."

"Peasegood," Bones said, keeping her wand pointed straight at Milo, "get the Veritaserum."

"Oh, right," Milo said. "That." The Ministry had used it on him back in First Year, when they'd tried to prove he wasn't human or something. As if his bonus feat wasn't proof enough of his humanity. "Last time you used that on me, everything I said was dismissed from evidence as delusional," he reminded them. "What makes you think this time will be any different? I can't give testimony. I'm insane. I think I'm from another world, remember?"

From somewhere under the table, Peasegood produced a tiny vial of a clear, colourless liquid.

"Wait," Bones said. She made a sharp, horizontal slash with her wand. "Diffindo." Milo's Amulet of Protection from Good fell from his neck as the silver links of its chain were severed.

"That was brand new!" Milo complained.

"You understand we can use magic to force you to drink this if you resist, correct?" Bones said.

"I would nod if I could move my neck," Milo said. "I'll drink."

"Good. Don't make this more difficult than it needs to be."

Veritaserum was completely tasteless, which would be a perfect opportunity for a pun if (drip-DRIP… drip) Milo wasn't so distracted by the thrice-cursed dripping noise.

"Let's start off with some test questions, shall we?" Peasegood said. "What is your name?"

"Milo Amastacia-Liadon."

"How old are you?"

"Uh…" Milo said. "I'm not entirely certain. I died, and that complicates the issue. Next question?"

Peasegood blinked. "You're dead?"

The great thing about Common (English, as they called it here) is that it's probably the worst language ever devised. It allows anyone with a slippery enough mind and apprentice-knowledge of grammar to get past all kinds of magical truth-telling effects.

In this case: take the phrase 'you're dead.' Peasegood likely intended the contraction 'you're' to mean 'you are.' But, technically, Milo had no way of knowing for sure that Peasegood didn't mean 'you were.' At minimum, he had plausible deniability. The truthful answer to the first interpretation was 'no,' but for the second, equally correct interpretation…

"Dead as THAC0, yeah." Just because Milo had to tell the truth didn't mean he wasn't allowed to mess with his captors. Besides, right this moment, Mordy was probably out there somewhere organizing a rescue for him. The Familiar could find him from anywhere within a mile, and it wouldn't take a genius to figure out that he was being held by the Ministry somewhere. On the other hand, Milo couldn't feel anything from his bond with the rat, but that just meant that he was simply still on his way. Hopefully.

"Peasegood, check his pulse," Bones ordered. "I can't even remember how many times I told Fudge we ought to have this place consecrated against the undead. But he always claims it would offend our 'metabolically-impaired cousins.'"

Peasegood placed two fingers on Milo's neck for twenty seconds. "He's lying."

"Impossible," Bones said. "Nobody his age can lie under the effects of Veritaserum. It's unheard of."

"Like being able to casually block Unforgivable Curses?" Milo added helpfully. "So far I'm three for three against them."

Bones glanced at Peasegood uncertainly. Milo got the feeling that she wasn't used to uncertainty. He was also starting to get the feeling that not everything with Bones was quite hot it seemed.

"You claim that you died," Peasegood said, stepping in after Bones' hesitation. "How did this come about?"

"Well, you asked me about my age, and I—"

"I would advise against further facetiousness, boy."

Milo struggled briefly against the ropes once more. "That was supposed to be another shrug. Fine, have it your way. You-Know-Who offed me in the Chamber of Secrets last year."

"Pretend, for a moment, that we don't know who," Peasegood said. "Don't think you're the first to use the phrase 'you-know-who' under Veritaserum to imply a deceased Dark Wizard as cover for another. A Dark Wizard, by the way, who has been deceased for a decade now."

Milo rolled his eyes. He still had that amount of control, at least. "He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named. But you knew that already."

Peasegood glanced at Bones, now sharing her uncertainty.

"You can drop the act," Milo said. "We both know you two aren't calling the shots in this conversation."

Amelia Bones simply shrugged in response, but Peasegood's expression went completely blank, almost as if he'd been switched off. "How did you survive, boy?"

"I was brought back to life by magic," Milo said.

"Impossible," Bones said. "I am closer than anyone to immortality. You must have used some form of trick. A patsy, perhaps, controlled from afar with the Imperius Curse and disguised as you through means of Polyjuice."

"You lived in my head for the better part of a year," Milo said. He didn't often get the chance to really tick off the campaign's BBEG, and he decided he'd make the most of it while he could. "You know I'm not like other wizards; I can do things you've only dreamed of. Death is really no obstacle for me."

"Bellatrix tells me that you don't feel pain," Bones said in a low voice. "She says the Cruciatus Curse has no impact on you."

"You saw that firsthand last year," Milo said. He really wished he could shrug, it would make the whole 'nonchalant in the face of danger' act much more convincing. And fun. "Veritaserum makes me tell the truth, but it doesn't make me answer you. You won't get any useful information out of me. There's not a lot you can actually do to me short of killing me," Milo said, "so why don't we get this over with?" His best bet, as far as he could tell, was annoying Riddle—who he was now completely certain was controlling Bones and Peasegood—to the point where he slipped up and revealed something.

"Ah," Bones said, "But I don't need to kill you."

Milo frowned. He wasn't sure where this was going, but he didn't like it. She reached into her robes and pulled out a very large, very still, brown-and-white rat.

"Mordy," Milo whispered despite himself. "He's not—"

"Dead? No. Only Stunned—for now. Which is how he will remain, unless you answer my questions."

Milo swallowed. He doubted he could swing a deus ex machina for his Familiar, and even if he could, he wasn't sure it was possible. It was another gray area in the rules—dead Familiars could be replaced, but it wasn't clear if they could be brought back to life. No-one cared about them enough to find out. They weren't important. And even if they could be, the loss of a Familiar incurred massive XP damage on the animal's master, and Milo had lost enough levels for one day.

Beyond that, though, Mordenkainen was his Familiar, dammit. His responsibility—and his friend.

Drip… drip… … drip…

"What do you want to know?" Milo asked.

"Where does Harry Potter live when he's not at Hogwarts?"

Milo sighed. When it came down to it, he was just so tired. He'd already had his psyche steamrolled by the Dementor; all he wanted now was to go eat some more chocolate and maybe have a nap. He didn't want to have to pick between his Familiar and Harry. He had no spells, no plans, no Amulet of Protection from Evil/Good/Law/Chaos/Megalomaniacal Evil Wizards, and no-one who knew where he was. His hopes of rescue were dashed with the reveal that the possessed Ministry goons had taken his rat, too.

At the end of the day, he didn't really have any option. If he didn't tell Voldemort, then Mordy would die—and, in all likelihood, so would Milo. If he did spill the beans on Harry's summer home, then Harry would certainly die, while Milo and Mordy would almost certainly die.

"A conversation I had with my sister the other day got me thinking about resource allocation. You know, how X amount of money can buy one of Y or twenty of Z and whatnot. In my adventures, before I came to this world, my companions and I once encountered an isolated tribe eking it out in the ruins of a lost city; the descendants of an expedition sent to gather a rare form of privet shrub for perfume. It was terrible perfume—the smell of Number Four Privet Drives my sister crazy. They could barely scavenge enough food to survive, and almost every night one of them was picked off by a nearby band of troglodytes, or robbed by kobolds. They had no magic, barely any shelter, and practically no weapons—but the thing that really stood out to me was the socks. The majority of them went barefoot."

"I do assume that, sooner or later, you will get to the point," Bones said. "If you do not, your rat will die. Taking, as I understand it, much of your power with it."

"I'm getting there," Milo said. "You were, what, fifty or sixty when you lost your body?"

"Sixty-six," Bones said. "A problem that has since been remedied."

"Sure, sure. Now, for this next bit of the story, I need to make a couple of educated guesses. I don't know much about your world and its history, see. But I know that, back in Myra (City of Light! City of Magic!), an average person bought six pairs of socks every year. You can thank the incredible number of skill ranks I've thrown into various Knowledge skills over the years for that fact. They weren't stockpiling them, though; those socks were just to replace their losses."

"You're stalling, now."

"I'm not. You can believe me, because I'm under Veritaserum, that I'm getting to your answer. Just bear with me for a moment. I'm assuming, because people are so much richer, that people here get more socks than the Azelan peasants did. You strike me like a rich kid, so I'm going to take a wild guess and say you could get replacements for the ones you lost Under a Staircase whenever you wanted with a Little Whinging, and as such you went through somewhere around ten pairs of socks a year. That's six hundred and sixty pairs of socks before you were en-tome-ed, pardon the pun, in that diary."

Drip… drip…

"You have twenty seconds before I kill your rat."

"There were only a hundred and twenty-three people in the tribe when I saw them. I bet they would take better care of their socks than you do, because they wouldn't be able to replace their losses. They wouldn't lose them at night, they wouldn't throw them out because they were too lazy to darn them. I bet they could get a solid year out of a single pair of socks, and they'd get a lot more enjoyment out of them than you did. They'd be among their most treasured possessions. Six hundred and sixty pairs of socks could keep that entire tribe's feet warm for five years. I'm sure there's places like that in your world, too."

"Five… Four… Three…."

" You're interested in finding Harry Potter. I understand that. But Harry Potter's my friend. You've been in my head long enough that you know that I don't let anything happen to my friends. I take precautions to protect them. I've made a series of bolt-holes for my friends to hide in the summers, if need be. One such hiding place is one hundred and seven miles due south of Hogwarts concealed beneath an oak tree that's been split by lightning. If I were you, I would look there first for Harry Potter in the summer. Here's my point: if your mother had had the common decency to simply strangle you when you were first born, and the socks you wasted in life were given to the needy, that's twelve-hundred combined foot-years of warmth added to the world. I know where I'm going when I die," Milo said. "I've seen it. Remember, I'm under the effects of Veritaserum, so you can believe that I believe what I'm about to say is one hundred percent true, you are a gods-damn waste of socks, Riddle. But it's a moot point, because I'll end you well before then. If you want to live to see that summer, you may as well just kill me again. Now let my rat go."

Everything Milo said was technically true. He'd even said precisely where Harry lived between school years. And if he were Voldemort, he would look under random trees and in forests to find Harry, because completely wasting his time would be better for the world than trying to succeed on his objectives. Were Milo Voldemort, he'd also very likely drown himself.

Amelia Bones' eyes twitched. She pointed her wand at Mordenkainen, and began to speak. "I think not. Avada Ke—"

The door behind her opened quickly, flooding the room with light. A tall, ancient man wearing horribly-clashing purple and magenta robes stood in the doorway, his white beard almost reaching his waist. A dozen or so witches and wizards of various description peered into the room curiously.

"And here we have the famous third lower janitorial closet, considered enormously significant among janitorial historians due to its—oh, pardon me," the man said, peering over his half-moon spectacles. "This isn't the third lower janitorial closet at all. In fact, unless I am quite mistaken, these are the long-unused Department of Magical Law Enforcement interrogation cells. Not to be re-opened except in times of war. Clearly, there has been some misunderstanding."

"Dumbledore?" Milo choked out. He could hardly believe it. No, scratch that—when it came to Dumbledore, he could believe anything.

"In fact, a number of mistakes seem to have been made," Dumbledore said, looking at his little visitor's badge. "Not the least that I am, in fact, not a tour guide. Do forgive me, it's a mistake anyone could have made. Much like accidentally, and, I'm afraid, quite illegally, interrogating a minor without just cause or due process."

The Imperiused Bones stared at Dumbledore completely disbelievingly for a moment before rallying.

"No visitors!" she snapped. "How did you even get in here? The door was locked!"

"Yes, I did quite wonder about that," Dumbledore said, giving Milo a quick wink. He turned back to his tour group. "The third lower janitorial closet hasn't been locked since—can anyone tell me?"

"Since the Goblin Uprisings of 1743," Milo called out, choosing to fully embrace the surreal. "When they were used as a last refuge by Ministry staff in an attempt to escape the reprisals."

"Bravo!" Dumbledore said. "Two points for Gryff—oh, excuse me. I'm not a professor anymore, either. I'll have to write Minerva after this tour—" he gasped quite authentically, looking at the tour group as if it was his first time seeing it. "Dear me, things do seem to be going wrong today!" he exclaimed. "This isn't a tour group; it's the entire assembled Wizengamot!"

"Everybody out!" Peasegood shouted, snapping out of his neutral, switched-off expression. "This is a restricted area!"

"Indeed it is, young man," Dumbledore said. "Would you believe, however, that this badge"—he pointed at his visitor's badge—"says that I'm the Chief Warlock of the Wizengamot, incidentally the highest court in the land—speaking metaphorically, of course, not geographically—and that, therefore, in legal matters, I rather outrank you? Believe me, I'm quite as surprised as you are! I'm sure they'll sort all this out sooner or later, but in the meantime, I'm going to have to suspend this illegal interrogation and bring this child to where he belongs. All in favour?" Dumbledore glanced back at the Wizengamot, most of whom nervously raised their hands, clearly feeling out of their depth. "Very well, motion passed." Dumbledore flicked his wand casually, and the ropes holding Milo to the wall were severed.

Bones looked like she was trying very hard not to murder everyone in sight—which, now that Dumbledore was in the room, Milo doubted she would be capable of, Dark Lord-possession or no. At the very least, with the door now open, she couldn't guarantee that there would be no witnesses.

"Let's go, Milo," Dumbledore said, holding out his free hand.

"Wait," Milo said. First, he grabbed his broken Amulet and stuffed it in a pocket. Then he held out his hand to Amelia Bones. He could hear her teeth grinding from where he was standing as she grudgingly shoved Mordy into Milo's hands.

"Get out," she hissed, her knuckles clenched to white.

Milo practically skipped out through the doorway with Dumbledore.

"How did you know I was here?" he asked when they were alone.

"A little bird told me," Dumbledore said. "Or, more accurately, a little bird carrying a letter from an informant I have in the Ministry. I shouldn't go into further detail, the Ministry is maze-like."

Milo frowned. "Maze-like?"

"Yes, in that it is like maze."

It is… like maze? Milo stared at Dumbledore blankly. "I think you're missing a word that sentence."

"Maize as in corn."

"Oh. That… explains absolutely nothing."

Dumbledore sighed. "American corn grows in ears."

The copper piece dropped. "You're saying the walls have ears," he said, feeling a little silly.

"Naturally. Are you all right?" Dumbledore asked seriously.

"I think so," Milo said. "Bones and Peasegood are being Imperius'd by You-Know-Who, though." Milo frowned at his broken Amulet. "And so might I be, for that matter. My memories might not be my own at this point. Make sure I cast a Protection spell on myself when I next prepare my spells."

"Alas," Dumbledore said, "for I have been sacked, and can't go with you to Hogwarts. But I can ask Minerva to do so."

"That'll work," Milo said. "We don't want a repeat of what happened last year."

"If I may ask," Dumbledore said, "what did happen last year? For, I must confess, I believed you to be dead. Wait, no, do not answer me. It is the nadir of manners to ask personal questions of one under the effects of Veritaserum. We can discuss this matter later."

"How did you know they drugged me?" Milo asked.

"I do not mean to boast, but one does not get to be the Supreme Mugwump of the International Confederation of Wizards by collecting bottle caps, Milo. Though I did, I must say, have a modest collection in my office at Hogwarts. I wonder what Severus has done with it."

"Fair enough," Milo said. "Can we finally go to Hogwarts now? I feel like this campaign is already half over."

"Of course," Dumbledore said. "Take my hand."

Chapter 19: The Grim and the Grave

"Divinations," Milo said, looking at his timetable. He reached onto his shoulder and patted his rat on the head. "Do you see that, Mordy? We have Divinations next. I am going to be so good at this."

Even without his spellbook, Milo still had access to dozens, maybe hundreds, of Wizard Divination spells through his Spontaneous Divinations ability.

All the schedule said was 'top of the North Tower' by way of instructions. He tagged along with Neville and Hannah, who had a good sense of direction in Hogwarts' re-arranging hallways, up to the mysterious North Tower. Though they'd been confident at the outset, they quickly ran into problems.

"I wish they'd given us a map," Neville said, huffing and puffing for breath after their third wrong turn, "or actual directions." They were standing at a T-intersection, totally stumped.

"It's like they want us to be late," Hannah agreed. "This place is impossible to find. I'm starting to doubt the 'North Tower' is actually even on the north end of the castle…"

Milo shrugged. "It's a test," he said, his mind racing. "Divinations is the art of discovering information with magic. This is something your magic and mine actually have in common, based on what I've read. If we can't find the classroom, we're clearly not ready to learn from the top Diviner in the land."

"Oh?" Hannah asked. "How do we know he or she is so good?"

"Dumbledore only hires the best. What Professor McGonagall is to Transfiguration and Gilderoy Poptart was to Defence, this…" he glanced at the timetable, "'Professor Trelawney' will be to Divinations. Trust me. By June, when we'll be using our newfound mastery of Divinations to navigate the halls of Hogwarts with expertise, we'll be struck by the contrast between how hard we find this now and how easy it will be then. In fact, I'd bet copper to gold that the tower moves from week-to-week for that exact reason."

"We'll see," Hannah said skeptically. "I'm not sure you're right more often than a magic eight-ball when it comes to this stuff."

"I should get my hands on one of those, then," Milo said, imagining a powerful crystal ball. "It'd make my job easier. So what do you guys think: right or left?" He was beginning to wish he'd used a ball of string to mark their path. He wasn't one hundred-percent-sure that they hadn't been here before.

"If it helps," Mordy said, sniffing at the air, "From the right, I can smell… chamomile, mint, traces of bergamot, maybe some sandalwood. From the left…" he sniffed again. "…Mr. Filch."

Milo repeated this new information to Hannah and Neville.

"Right it is," Hannah said.

They were the first to arrive at the entrance to the classroom: a trapdoor on the ceiling with no obvious ladder or other means of entrance. A plaque read 'Sybill Trelawney, Divinations teacher.'

"Well, that's clearly it," Hannah mused. "But how do we get in?"

"Child's play," Milo said, reaching into his Belt of Many Things. He gripped his hand on a polished wooden stock and pulled, withdrawing a very complicated device. It resembled a light crossbow, but with a spool of fifty feet of rope attached to it, and a spiked grappling hook in place of a bolt. As an experienced adventurer, scaling walls to reach trapdoors was right up his alley. It could only be better if the trapdoor led to a fifteen-foot square room with an orc guarding a chest.

There were a host of magical ways he could get up to that door, from a simple Levitation spell to creating a steep bridge with Dark Way, but for nostalgia's sake, Milo decided to go with an old classic instead.

Neville had a sense for these sorts of things by this point, and took a few surreptitious steps to his right.

Hannah, on the contrary, lit up like a Will-o-Wisp. "A grapnel gun," she breathed as Milo turned the crank. It was only the work of a moment, despite his frail arms and the massive force stored inside the wood of the weapon. Historically, depending on level of training, strength, and the design of the crossbow, a professional crossbowman could achieve at most one to two shots per minute with such a device. But even the weakest, most novice Commoner child of Milo's world could maintain a rate of sustained fire approximately ten times that, requiring only a Move Action to reload.

Milo pressed the stock to his cheek and took aim at the trapdoor.

"Can I try?" Hannah asked eagerly. It would be simple enough to turn my spare robe into a cape and cowl… she mused. All I'd need then are batarangs.

Milo shrugged and passed the grapple-firing crossbow to her. Neville ducked as the business-end of the weapon swung past his face. "Just point and click," he said. "Couldn't be simpler."

Hannah gingerly took the weapon and aimed.

"Shatter," Milo muttered. The trapdoor exploded into splinters as Hannah fired, and the grappling hook flew through the opening. There was a clink-clink-clink as the hook dragged along the stone floor before anchoring itself on the lip. A particularly viciously-splintery chunk of wood crashed into the ground where Neville had stood but a moment before.

"I'll go up first," Milo said. "If things go wrong, I can heal."

The rope was close enough to the wall that he could sort of 'walk' up the wall using his arms as support, which wasn't exactly fun but got the job done.

When he finally pulled himself through the wreckage of the trapdoor (getting splinters stuck in his robes, to his annoyance) he was greeted with two enormous eyes locked directly at his.

"What did you do to my door!?" the creature shrieked.

Milo recoiled and almost fell, but the creature grabbed him by his collar and yanked him away from the hole.

It was then that he realized that the creature was, in fact, human. The giant eyes were really enormous spectacles worn by one of the strangest people he had ever seen. Her clothes were concealed behind dozens of chains, bangles, rings, and beads, the weight of which nearly caused her slight frame to buckle.

When Milo was put back on the ground, his foot brushed against a silvery rope ladder, which he kicked down the hole behind him. It would be a substantially speedier ascent than on the rope, he reasoned, and the longer he was away from the rest of the party, the more his teeth itched.

A glance down the hole told him that the other students were beginning to assemble down there, looking up in confusion at the splintered trap door. A great 'ahhhhh' of realization rose up from the crowd when they saw Milo's face, now knowing who was responsible.

"Sorry," Milo apologized. "I didn't see any other way up here."

"This simply won't do," the strange woman—Professor Trelawney, presumably—said. "I'll have to get Hagrid to make a new one. It could take days. Five points from…" she eyed Milo up and down. "…Hufflepuff?"

"Slytherin," Milo lied baldly.

"Very well," she said. "Five points from Slytherin, then."

As the other students filed in, Professor Trelawney glided over to a large armchair by the fire. The classroom itself was bizarre, even by Hogwarts standards. Rather than rows of chairs and desks, the room looked like a tavern for high elves. The floorspace was packed with small circular tables, armchairs, and pouffes. The combination of being at one of the highest points in the castle, the crackling fireplace, and the lack of windows or air flow made Milo yearn for the Endure Elements effect of his old robes. The walls were lined with spell components and foci, from candles to feathers to sticks of incense and bone runes—curiously, etched in Dwarven. Milo wondered if, given that Common was identical to this world's English, all of his world's languages had a local equivalent.

"Welcome," Trelawney said as they found seats. "How nice to see you in the physical world at last."

Milo nodded. It made sense; a Diviner who rarely left her tower would still have many ways of observing the goings-on in the castle. She likely would have been a huge help last year in finding Slytherin's Monster, had they only known to ask her. He'd only just sat down before whipping out a stack of paper and a quill and began jotting notes:

-local Divination seems largely equivalent to mine

"Welcome to Divination," Trelawney said. "I am Professor Trelawney. You may not have seen me before. I find that descending too often into the hustle and bustle of the main school clouds my Inner Eye."

-Double-movement and crinoline skirts provide penalties to local Divinations.

Milo frowned, then underlined that last one, and added, "How to exploit?" Which he then circled several times. Could a skeleton hamster constantly double moving in a wheel replicate the 'hustle' effect, thus providing countermeasures against the local Scrying equivalent? Perhaps if the hamster was wearing a miniature bustle…

"So you have chosen to study Divination, the most difficult of all magical arts. I must warn you at the outset that if you do not have the Sight, there is very little I will be able to teach you. Books can only take you so far in this field…"

-Sight=True Sight? Arcane Sight? Darkvision?

Milo frowned as he heard Trelawney talk about books. Based on everything he'd heard Hermione say, in this world, people could learn virtually any skill or ability from a book. The kind of learning Trelawney was talking about—a combination of in-born ability and practical experience—was much closer to how he worked.

-Possible convergence of rules sets?

This he underlined several times as well.

"Many witches and wizards," Trelawney continued, "talented though they are in the area of loud bangs and smells and sudden disappearances, are yet unable to penetrate the veiled mysteries of the future. It is a Gift granted to few."

-Divinations possibly based on different ability score than other magic? Milo noted. He took in Trelawney's outlandish appearance and flamboyant clothing. Addendum: Possibly Charisma-based, he wrote. Milo frowned. Loud bangs, smells, and sudden disappearances pretty much exactly described his modus operandi.

This went on for a bit, with Trelawney proclaiming various vague but foreboding things about people in class before giving them their assignment: drinking tea.

"This is the kind of assignment I could get used to," Hannah said, sipping at the steaming cup and reclining in her armchair.

Milo couldn't help but agree. "Beats Potions," he said.

Once they'd finished the tea, they were to perform a complex maneuver with the teacup—swilling them three times with their left hand, then flipping the cup upside-down to allow the leaves to drain onto their saucer. That done, Milo traded saucers with Hannah and consulted his textbook.

"What do you see?" Hannah asked.

"Uhhh," Milo said, hoping he wasn't going to have to invest precious skill ranks into Profession (Tasseographer) as he looked at the amorphous blob, "could be a shambling mound, a gray ooze, or an otyugh. Hard to say. Oh, this bit here is a down arrow, which means…" he consulted the text book. "'No, Bad, or Wrong Direction.'"

Milo glanced around to check that no-one was watching, then surreptitiously spun Hannah's saucer around. "Nevermind," he said. "Make that an up arrow, for 'Yes, Good, or Right Direction.' So that's some good news. Do you see anything in mine?"

"Looks kind of like an eight-pointed star," Hannah said. "Like two squares overlapped at a right angle. It would have been perfect, except one of the points is a weird blob."

"Can I see?" Milo asked, peering over at his own vision. Hannah was right—the tea leaves did form a surprisingly regular eight-pointed star, except for one point, which was deformed. Milo wondered if he'd slipped slightly flipping the teacup and messed up his fortune. "What's the book say that means?"

"Well…" she scanned the book. "There's the eight-pointed star of chaos, but that's more like a wheel with pointy bits coming out, and much less geometric."

"That's a relief," Milo said. "So it's nothing then? That was always a possibility. Trelawney said without the Sight that—"

"I think it's a copper's badge," Hannah said suddenly.

"Where's that?" Milo flipped through the book looking for the symbol.

"It's not in there," she said. "Look—seven points, but the top point is the crown."

"How can you tell it's copper?" Milo asked. "Everything's tea-coloured."

"No, uh…" Hannah thought for a moment. "Copper as in police. A guard," she clarified. "Like the Muggle woman at the train station that also arrested you at Harry's place."

"Iiiinteresting," Milo said slowly. "She seemed like a dead end to me."

"Maybe it's saying you should reach out to her?" Hannah asked. "Though it just as easily could be a warning. Maybe we should ask the professor."

As if on cue, Trelawney cried out from across the room. "The Grim, my dear, the Grim! The giant, spectral dog that haunts churchyards! My dear boy, it is an omen—the worst omen—of death!"

Milo whirled around to see what was going on. Harry, Ron, and Hermione were sitting together on a table on the far side of the room. Harry looked pale, and all eyes in the class were on him.

Milo frowned, deep in thought. Other students rushed over to examine Harry's tea leaves and examine the Grim for themselves, but Milo sat very still.

An omen of death. What could that possibly mean? As a rule, Milo was very, very cautious around predictions of the future. Magic, especially Divinations, could be a very reliable source of information about the present, and occasionally even the past, but the future?

Milo wasn't going to rule it out, but it brought up a bunch of very tricky questions around free will and self-fulfilment. For instance, say Harry was foretold to slip in mud on Tuesday but, knowing the prophecy, chose to stay indoors, then how could the prophecy have foretold that he would do so, and so on. Those kinds of conundrums Milo had seen analyzed to death even in fiction from his world. The most popular genre of such fiction was pure fantasy, that is, fiction that speculated a world without a DM (Deterministic Meddler).

Was this 'Grim' a sign of the DM showing its hand? Its intent to railroad? Milo shuddered at the thought.

In the example earlier—that Harry had seen an omen to slip in mud on Tuesday—the DM could simply force Harry to go outdoors. This could be anywhere from subtle ('the fastest way to your next classroom is through the courtyard…') to overt ('you have a vision informing you that if you don't go outside right now you'll die and the universe will end.').

The way Milo saw it, there were four possible interpretations for Harry's tea leaves:

The first: Professor Trelawney, a Hogwarts professor who is therefore held to the same standards as the likes of Professors Snape and McGonagall, had made an error.

The second: The DM was announcing its intention to railroad Harry on a path towards death. The omen didn't specify that it would be Harry who would die, necessarily, but still, few interpretations of the omen could be considered good. This was the worst-case scenario: if the DM would strip away Harry's free will like that, then it stood to reason that the DM would intervene and railroad on anything that went against its plan, and therefore this whole exercise was pointless and Milo could have stayed home in Myra (Cityoflight!Cityofmagic!), and doing so would have made no difference.

The third: Everyone was reading way too much into this omen. Perhaps, rather than literally revealing the truth of the future, the tea-leaf-reading-exercise was more of a nudge. Maybe a die was rolled against a table to reveal your fortune (in which case, a natural '1' was certainly this 'Grim'), and, depending on your roll, you got a bonus or penalty to a relevant die roll for a few days or some such. In this example, a vision of 'death' would probably result in a penalty to Fortitude saves, or possibly any saving throw against a death effect. The details were pure conjecture, but it was somewhat similar to, for example, the Cleric spell Omen of Peril—also, on the subject, a Divination spell.

The fourth: rather than an omen at all, the tea leaves were providing clues to the plot. In this case, if Hannah's interpretation were correct, Milo ought to speak to that Muggle woman again, and Harry ought to look out for large dogs—on that subject, there was only one large dog that Milo had seen recently, and that was the Animagus-form of Sirius Black.

Milo ruled the first option right out; he couldn't imagine Snape messing up a potion or McGonagall a transfiguration. The second option he had no choice but to dismiss; regardless of its truth, there would be absolutely nothing he could do about it. In the case of the third option, there wasn't a whole lot Milo could or should do beyond keep a close eye on Harry for a couple of days. But in the fourth, there was clear action to take.

The only problem was that little idea who or where that woman was, and therefore, very limited opportunity to follow up on the clue.

Milo looked up. The classroom was empty save for himself and Trelawney, who was staring at him expectantly.

"Oh," Milo said, standing up. "Sorry." He hurried down the silver ladder (reclaiming his grappling hook and rope as he did so) and hurried to catch up with the other students, who were heading to the Great Hall for lunch.

o—o—o—o

Fiona slipped through the crowds of Diagon Alley. She wore a ratty black hooded bathrobe from the Salvation Army over her borrowed clothes with the hood pulled up over her face. She'd lost her cane and old disguise when Malfoy burned down her flat, but was just able to manage a slow hobble without its aid. Travis' car was parked in a garage nearby; finding parking near Diagon Alley was surprisingly easy as wizards, it seemed, seldom bothered with Muggle means of transportation. She kept her face and eyes low, trying to avoid a repeat of the last time she was here, which seemed so very long ago now.

Eventually she made her way to the owl post office and slipped inside. She placed a knut and an envelope on the filthy table and left. She hobbled back through the crowded alley, the brick gateway, and the pub, and let out an explosive breath when she was back on the busy streets of London. She was shaking again.

Get a GRIP, Fiona, she scolded herself. She wondered, for a moment, if maybe skipping out on mandatory counselling hadn't been her wisest choice. She dismissed the notion and instead made for her borrowed car. She had a long way to go before she could rest.

o—o

Her response came when she was stuck in traffic caused by roadwork on a highway, based on the tourist bus that she was stuck in front of, just south of Hadrian's Wall. An owl landed on the hood of her car and pecked rapidly on the glass.

"Okay, okay," she eased, rolling down the driver-side window. The owl flew through the window and landed on the dash, sticking one leg out obediently. There was a piece of paper tied around its leg, which was something she'd never get used to.

Seeing as how the highway was virtually a parking lot anyway at this point, she figured she'd make the most of her time and read the letter on the spot.

The response was what she'd hoped for, which was a relief.

Unless it was a trap.

Fiona drummed her fingers on the steering wheel. Of late, everything had started to look like a trap.

It's not paranoia if there really are memory-erasing wizards out to get you, she reminded herself. Probably. She was sure her counsellor would have had something to say about that.

A long, angry honk told Fiona that traffic had begun to move. She reached a hand out the open window, flipped off the car behind her, then used a blue Bic crystal pen to write a hurried response on the back of the parchment (idly wondering if she was the first person ever to do something so anachronistic) and tied it back on the owl's leg. The owl bit her finger lightly, and Fiona remembered what she'd forgotten, and gave the bird a knut.

Seemingly satisfied, the owl took off through the window once more. Fiona hit the gas and the car lurched into motion, heading north.

o—o—o—o

The city, at least this part of it, was primarily dark, gothic stone that had been stained unevenly black from coal soot over the centuries. The taller and older the building, the more it looked like it had survived a terrible fire. Only these soot-blackened spires were visible through the thin fog from this height.

Milo wondered if it had been built originally by dwarves. Most of the buildings were made out of chiselled sandstone, and the enormous, sheer hills that rose out of the streets had a very 'mountain home' sort of vibe, though the stained black gothic stonework screamed 'don't forget your garlic and holy symbols.'

"Over there, I think," Milo said, pointing at the tall steeple of a temple to some local deity. He and Hannah were floating high above the city on her broomstick, concealed in their black robes against the night sky. The letter had asked him to come alone, but since the Dementor had taken away his ability to Teleport, he needed a ride. Enclosed in the letter had been an extraordinarily detailed painting of the place they were to meet—it was a like a coloured, non-moving image from the Daily Prophet—with the message written on the back. Hannah called it a 'postcard.'

The temple was surrounded by a huge graveyard; the grave markers were blackened sandstone like the buildings were. Several had crumbled over the centuries; the caretakers, were there any, were apparently content to leave them where they fell. Hannah dropped them gracefully behind a particularly grand one whose writing had long since worn away.

Milo loved graveyards. There was absolutely zero way this meeting was going to end without him mowing down hordes and hordes of skeletons, and he relished the XP that would provide. If he played his cards right, he might even be able to Teleport them back home.

"She doesn't know you're going to be here," Milo said, "So you should try to lurk nearby. Be the ace in the hole in case something happens."

"I'm fine being an ace," Hannah said, "but do I have to be in a hole? It's cold and damp out."

A light flicked on, almost blinding Milo in the darkness. It didn't flicker like torchlight, but was steady and clear, and therefore almost certainly magical in nature.

Holding the light in one hand was the Muggle woman that had arrested him over a year ago, and who he had seen in the train station earlier in September. She leaned heavily against a crumbling tombstone with her other hand. Her bloodshot eyes were weighed down with heavy bags, and her greasy hair was pulled into a clumsy bun.

This was a woman on the brink, Milo was certain, though the brink of what was less clear.

"I said come alone," she muttered. "Didn't think you would though. Your kind always flaunts the rules." She narrowed her eyes and her tone became sharp and commanding. "Keep your hands where I can see them. Drop the broomstick."

Milo shrugged and complied. He nudged Hannah to get her to as well.

"Hold up," she said, carefully leaning her broomstick against a grave marker. "I don't want it to get all muddy and wet. We're riding home on this, remember."

Milo sighed. At times, Hannah could have very little flair for the dramatic.

"Who are you?" Milo asked. "Why did you reach out to me?"

The woman's eyes flicked around the graveyard. "Not here," she said, almost as if to herself. "They've known about this location for hours. Keep them on their toes. Don't let them prepare. Who knows what shit they've got hidden out here." She spoke up again, clearly addressing Milo and Hannah. "Come with me," she said. "It's not far."

"Erm," Hannah interjected. "Can I bring my Cleansweep Seven? My parents bought it for my birthday; I don't want to lose it."

The woman blinked twice, then nodded, slowly leading them out of the graveyard. She moved from tombstone to tombstone, taking limping, uneven steps in-between. Frankly, it was painful to watch.

Wordlessly, Milo withdrew his quarterstaff from his Belt of Hidden Pouches and passed it to her. She looked at him suspiciously, but accepted the staff. After that, they made much better time as she leaned heavily on the darkwood shaft.

Milo flinched as they entered the street. Bright lights illuminated the foggy city, and a Muggle self-propelled car the size of the legendary Tarrasque barreled past him at unearthly speeds. Another car, this one small and Slaad-red, zoomed after it.

"Boccob!" Milo cursed, pressing himself flat against the wall as far from the street as he could manage. He broke into a cold sweat thinking about the damage an object moving that fast would do to his feeble d4-hit die spellcaster frame.

The woman ignored him and pressed on, but Hannah moved to his other side.

"I'll stay between you and the traffic," she said. "I guess it can seem pretty intense compared to a horse-and-buggy, huh? If you stay on this raised area, you'll be fine."

Milo nodded mutely, and tried to look anywhere other than towards the street as he followed the Muggle woman.

"Thanks," he said quietly. He was mortified at this display of weakness in front of the Muggle.

He'd just got the hang of walking along-side traffic when the woman evidently decided to succumb to latent suicidal urges and boldly walked straight into the street. Their island of raised concrete had run out.

To his horror, Hannah followed the woman, seemingly without a second thought.

Milo froze at the edge of the raised concrete perimeter to the street. There weren't any cars coming in his direction right now, but he could barely conceive of their speed as it was and visibility was poor. It would only be the work of a moment for another behemoth to barrel around the corner, and all that would be left of Milo would be a hefty chunk of XP for the driver.

Hannah was halfway across the street when, as if just to further raise Milo's anxiety, she stopped and turned around to look at him.

"Come on," she said, standing perfectly still right in the path of the gargantuan hyper-fast death machines.

Milo simply shook his head mutely. This was madness. Fighting monsters was one thing—there was always a chance of victory—but this was psychotic.

Hannah held out her hand. "Trust me," she said. "It's perfectly safe. The lights direct traffic to wait while we cross."

Milo swallowed. He didn't trust any magical lights directing him where to go (never trust something if you don't know where it keeps its brain), but he did trust Hannah…

Milo broke into a run across the street, figuring that if he was going to risk death, he may as well risk it for as brief a time as possible. Hannah grabbed his hand midway through his sprint and pulled him to the alleged safety of the raised concrete.

"Jesus Christ," the Muggle woman muttered. "You've got to be kidding me. We're just going two more blocks. Are you going to make it?"

Milo nodded, well aware of the irony of a woman with a leg injury asking him if he'd make it to their mysterious destination.

The next two streets were Hell itself, but eventually they reached a small café that, based on the sign outside, would barely be open for another hour.

"Here we are," the woman said. The entrance area resembled a miniature gift shop of sorts, selling toys and more Muggle "postcards," most of them elephant-themed.

"I think it'll be safe to talk here," the woman said. "No shadowy nooks, no hidden corners. Lots of witnesses." She nodded at the café staff who, even at this hour, were working through a long line of customers. "They also make a mean Earl Grey." She held out her hand to Milo and forced a smile. "I'm Fiona Smythe," she said, "Surrey Police." She hesitated. "Probably former Surrey Police. I haven't been able to check the post in a few days, but I'm sure the news wouldn't be good if I did. We met the other day at King's Cross."

Milo shook her hand. "Milo Amastacia-Liadon," he said. "But we've met before then."

Fiona gave her head a small shake. "So they tell me. Grab a seat, I'll get you two some hot cocoa. I suspect we have a lot to talk about."

Chapter 21: Light Treason

"The world is round, Milo," Hannah explained wearily.

"Shut the front door!" Milo exclaimed, nearly dropping his chalk.

It was Friday evening in an empty classroom. This castle was enormous—Milo wasn't convinced that the interior occupied the same physical space as the exterior—and there tended to be dozens of rooms not currently in use. He liked to move around, switching rooms from time to time, to throw off any potential spies and assassins.

His current secret room was full of chalkboards covered in mathematical equations, diagrams, and maps of England—the kind that crazy people on TV have, that are covered in brightly-coloured strings of yarn for no obvious reason. There were stacks of thousands and thousands of maps, some with accurate latitude and longitude, and others unironically labelled 'Here be Dragons.' It was, in short, perfect for Milo's needs.

"How can the world be both limitless and round?" Milo asked, convinced he'd scored a point. "Answer that."

"It's not limitless," Hannah sighed, rubbing a pair of fingers into her forehead.

"But look at the edges of this map," Milo protested, pointing at a yellowed map that still had Prussia on it. "See? Oceans on either end. Who knows what's across them—that's the point! The DM—that is to say, the Divine Mapper—can just bolt on an extra continent for the next adventure with some scrap paper and sellotape."

"The world is round, like a ball," Hannah explained, mounting what she considered to be a heroic effort to maintain patience. "Those oceans are the same, see how they're labelled—okay, well, this map just says "Fathomless Blue Yonder," but you'll see the newer ones agree that both edges are the Pacific. See where it says "Pacific" in plain English? If you go off one end, you come back around the other."

"That… makes this more complicated than I'd first believed," Milo admitted.

His plan had been so simple to start. Circle Dance, a third-level Divination spell, told you the exact direction (but not distance) to any one person that you named and had met before. Back home, it was common practice to use two castings of Circle Dance, cast in different locations, to triangulate the exact current location of your target. All you'd need is a bit of math, typically handled by a Knowledge (Architecture and Engineering) check. For added convenience, with a Familiar in five feet—as Mordenkainen was, currently—the spell would affect both of them, preventing the need to waste a second spell slot, though due to the extremely short distance between them, the math was done with a very large number of digits after the decimal point.

"You don't have a spell to do math for you?" Hannah asked. "You've got one to illegally copy textbooks. How is that possible?"

"If someone made one, they never published it," Milo said glumly. "You'd be surprised how rarely this comes up. Don't you guys have one?"

"We usually leave this sort of thing to the Muggles," Hannah admitted. "Actually, you know who would be great at this sort of thing—"

"We can do this without her help," Milo interrupted. "I just have to buckle down and make a skill check."

Milo rolled up his sleeves, strode purposefully up to the chalkboard, and drew a circle. He held the chalk in the air, staring at the circle for a moment, then, for good measure, added 'X =' next to it.

"You're just being stubborn," Hannah said. "This is important enough that we should suck it up and—"

"I've got this," Milo said, narrowing his eyes, then fell silent.

Minutes rolled by, with Milo standing perfectly unmoving, chalk hovering a millimeter above the board.

"We can't take any chances with this," Hannah said. "Get the equation wrong and we'll storm into the flat of some random bystander."

After a total lack of response, she waved a hand in front of his eyes. "Miiiiilo?" she asked, but he remained seemingly-catatonic. He was barely breathing.

Sighing, she sat down on a desk counter and waited.

And waited.

And waited.

After precisely twenty minutes of inactivity, Milo wrote an address, a floor, and a room number.

"Ye of little faith," he smirked. "Taking twenty solves all problems magical and mathematical. You could call me a—"

Hannah sighed. "Don't say 'mathmagician.'"

"—mathmagician. Let's rock and roll."

o—o—o—o

Fiona clutched the scrap of parchment, her sweat making the ink run. She was an hour from the nearest road, and her bad leg ached from the hike. Eventually, she found the rock described, which was the only feature distinguishing this sheep pasture from the dozen or so she'd passed along the way. They were in Weatherwax country, and boy was it boring. The rock itself was huge, sitting smack dab in the middle of the grassy field as if God had shaken it out of His holy sandal, then forgotten about it.

The whole while, she couldn't shake the feeling that she was being…

…watched.

An enormous black dog stood silhouetted on the hill against the setting sun, staring right at her, which was just about the creepiest thing she'd ever seen.

Keeping the dog in the corner of her eye, Fiona felt about the rock for the promised opening. Though they were on the other side of the country, this rock, exactly like the last one, de-materialized as she touched it. It was like one of those frustrating illusions, where the tacky fruit hat turned into a duck or whatever, depending on how you squinted at it. She could still see the rock, and it wasn't exactly transparent, but she could, just as clearly, see the tunnel heading down into the ground.

Her feet found simple wooden slats spiked into the earth that formed a crude staircase as she descended. She had to stoop, which her leg did not like, as the ceiling got lower and lower. It wasn't long before she had to fish a torch out of her pocket. It was one of those tiny ones, barely larger than the nine-volt battery that powered it, that lit up a room like a second sun but died practically as soon as you'd hit the button.

The room she illuminated was the twin of the one outside Bristol, complete with the medieval weaponry hanging on the walls. She found, and promptly collapsed onto, a crude wooden chair identical to the last one.

She wondered if this was what getting old felt like. It seemed like just a few days ago, she was a bright-eyed rookie, ready and eager to tackle the wrongs of the world. There had been such a clear line between right and wrong, then.

There was still wrong, that's for sure, and it was as clear as it had ever been. More so, now, that the gang she was after wore Hallowe'en masks and robes. It was the right that seemed ever-more amorphous.

What was she doing out here? Where had it all gone wrong? She has no job, no money, no family, no future. Most of her old classmates had kids by now, but what about her? A bum leg, a vendetta against evil, and a crappy torch?

She bent down to rub her aching leg when she noticed, blocking the only tunnel out, was the enormous black dog.

Reminding herself that, since monsters were in fact real and that this might well be a killer demon-dog doing the will of an evil shaman or something, she snatched the first thing off the weapon rack behind her that she saw—a five-foot pole with a razor-sharp spike-and-crescent-blade-shaped-blade-thingy on the end.

"Back off," she snapped at the animal, pointing the bizarre blade of the polearm at it. She glanced back at the weapon rack to see if there was anything a little less ridiculous on the menu, and when she looked back, the dog was gone.

In its place was a man who looked just about how her leg felt. He had long, dirty black hair with a piece of white sheep's wool stuck in it, and wore tattered old robes. Oddly, he looked almost exactly how Fiona had always pictured Aragorn when the hobbits first met him, though she wasn't sure if that was good new or not. Was it 'looked foul but felt fair,' or 'looked fair but felt foul?' How did smelling foul factor into the algorithm?

"I know you," Fiona said slowly, keeping the blade as steady as she could; an awkward maneuver given the torch she was also trying to balance. "You're Sirius Black. An escaped killer." She'd read about him in the Daily Prophet; allegedly, he was in cahoots with Milo, though she found that singularly unlikely. "You'll find I won't go down as easily as those bystanders in '87."

Sirius face turned stony. "I see," he said.

Just keep him talking, Fiona thought. He wasn't holding a wand, so she'd have a second or two of warning while he drew, twiddled it about, and muttered a spell before she died. Though, as he apparently could turn into a giant dog, he might not need a spell to kill her. Judging by movie standards, which was all she had to go on at this point, going full werewolf would take several seconds at least, and she felt no compulsion to sit around like a Sailor Moon villain during a lengthy transformation sequence. She didn't know what being stuck with a stupid-looking polearm while undergoing massive physical change would do to a person, but she hoped it wouldn't be good. All she had to do was buy enough time for reinforcements to arrive—they were already several minutes overdue.

Thirteen year olds, she reminded herself. That was her rescue plan. Children. Good God, what was she doing?

"Did Malfoy send you to finish me off?" she asked. "Is that why he sprung you from Alcatraz?"

"Azkaban," Sirius corrected flatly. "Where, it should be mentioned, they sent me without a trial."

Fiona frowned, and inadvertently lowered her blade-on-a-stick. "You're lying," she said, offended at the very idea of such a breach of due process. "Magical Britain is still Britain, and not even those nutters would do that."

"The star witness was Cornelius Fudge," Sirius explained.

Ah, so he's insane. She tried to imagine a murderer claiming that Margaret Thatcher had personally framed him for murder, and had to fight the urge to laugh.

"That's pretty unlucky," Fiona said, carefully watching her tone. "The Minister for Magic himself? That's a raw deal, any way you look at it."

"You think I'm crazy. I'm not crazy," Sirius snarled, taking a half-step forwards.

Fiona flinched, raising the blade to throat-height. "Back off," she snapped. "These are my only clothes, and I don't want to have to spend all night scrubbing arterial spray out of them."

Sirius froze. "Who are you?"

"Fiona!" the scandelized voice of a young boy came from the entrance. "Drop the guisarme! He's on our side! And with -4 to hit, you're better off using your bare hands!"

Fiona looked over Sirius's shoulder to see Milo and Hannah staring at them, horrified.

Slowly, she laid the weapon—the guisarme—on the table, watching Sirius closely as she did, ready to snatch it back up if need be.

"Fiona, this is Sirius Black," Milo explained rapidly. "An innocent man who took the fall for a crime he didn't commit—a classic hero backstory. Sirius, this is Fiona Smythe, the only Muggle to ever go toe-to-toe with Death Eaters and come out on top."

"Why would someone frame you?" Fiona asked suspiciously. "I've seen a lot of perps claim they've been framed over the years, and you know how many were on the level? Not one. Framing a person takes way more effort and planning than most criminals are capable of."

"These were no ordinary criminals," Sirius said. "They'd just murdered Lily and James Potter and needed to cover their tracks. They thought they were moments away from seizing power nationwide."

"Fine," Fiona said, deciding it wasn't worth arguing the point. "Even if that's true, why are you working with Milo? What does any of this have to do with you? You broke out of wizard prison; you should be halfway to Mallorca by now."

"Not until I finish what I started," Sirius said. "War's not over yet."

Fiona glanced at Milo. "Uh, this guy seems a little… unstable. Do we really need him?"

"He's our ride," Hannah interjected. "He can Apparate, and we can't."

"Time is short," Milo added. "We need to work together, don't you understand? There's four of us, now—and with you, we finally have a tank. This is practically a balanced party, for once! Four's the perfect number for fighting evil."

Fiona looked at his earnest, face and considered this barmy idea for a long moment. The balance of probability said she was already insane anyway, so why not add a werewolf into the mix? Besides, she was tired of going it alone. The weight of responsibility accumulated over the last year was slowly killing her, and at this point, she'd take any help she could get.

"Sure, what the Hell," she said eventually. "What have I got to lose? So, how does this work? Do we all just say 'Scotty, four for transport' and then zip away?"

"We'll Side-Along Apparate," Sirius said. "Stay close. Milo, where are we going?"

"23 Church Lane, ten feet three inches off the ground—the second storey," Milo said. "Godric's Hollow." He moved up next to Sirius and placed a hand on his arm. A second later, a huge rat scurried out of one of Milo's belt pouches and sat on Sirius' shoulder. Hannah was next also touching Sirius's arm, and Fiona reluctantly followed suit.

"Godric's Hollow, eh?" Sirius said in a voice so low it was almost a growl. "Fitting."

"We should teleport a little ways away, surveil the area, then plan a multi-pronged—"

"Nah," Sirius interrupted. That's when things got very strange.

It felt a little like someone grabbed Fiona's nose and pulled it backwards through her head, turning her entirely inside-out.

o—o—o—o

Alecto Carrow woke to the sound of breaking glass. She snatched the wand from under her pillow and climbed out of bed.

She knew, sooner or later, that it would come to this. She'd left a lot of enemies behind her over the years, and it was only a matter of time before one of them took matters into their own hands.

What she didn't know was who was making their move. The Order of the Phoenix was long since scattered to the winds, and the DMLE was in Lucius' pocket. Unless it was Lucius himself, coming to silence a loose end? Or Bellatrix, trying to whittle away Lucius's supporters?

Of course, it might just be her idiot brother coming home worse for drink, but she couldn't take that chance. Alecto pressed her back against the wall by the door, wand held at the ready, waiting for the attacker to enter.

The doorknob turned, and Alecto raised her wand. It was almost completely dark save for faint moonlight coming through the open windows, but her eyes had largely adapted to the night, and at this range she wouldn't need much in the way of aim. The door opened a crack. She decided to show some restraint and use a Stunner to get answers out of the intruder later.

"Stupe—"

The world went white as something akin to the Hogwarts Express smashed her head against the partially-open door. She slid to the ground to find herself pinned by a massive black animal. How had it got in? She'd watched the only door. Unless it had somehow climbed two floors of wall outside and entered through a window, but she'd never even heard of a dog doing something like that.

She spotted her wand on the carpet ahead of her, and struggled against the animal to reach it. Its claws raked her arm, but she managed to touch it with the tips of her fingers.

Almost there, she thought frantically. Then I can kill this mutt and get some answers.

Her fingers closed around the base of the wand. She raised it, mustering up the hatred for a Killing Curse—

"Shatter."

Her wand was gone, replaced by hundreds of splinters up and down her arm.

"Sirius!" a woman shouted. "Enough!"

The dog backed off of her, and rough hands grabbed her by the neck of her nightgown. A moment later, she was slammed back against the wall, face-to-face with that Muggle woman.

"You're nicked," Fiona spat. Alecto struggled futilely, but was spun around and pressed face-first into the wall. A moment later, something cold and metallic clamped around her wrists.

o—o—o—o

Fiona tossed the handcuffed witch into the cave's only chair.

"You're under arrest for…" she hesitated. What, exactly, was the crime associated with dressing up in masks and using magic to overthrow the government? "Oh, what the Hell. Treason. You're under arrest for suspicion of high treason."

"Wh-what?!" the woman scoffed. "You have no authority over me! You're just a Muggle!"

Fiona grinned an evil grin. "And you're a British citizen who's levied war against the Crown."

"What crown? Whose crown? What madness is this?" Alecto's eyes were wild. She looked around the room, seeing Sirius, Hannah, and finally, Milo. "You! I should have known you had a part in this! Everything that goes wrong in the world has your touch of madness."

"Flattery will get you nowhere," Milo said.

Alecto turned to Sirius. "Black! Get me out of this! Why would you fight on the side of those who unjustly threw you in Azkaban? Don't you want revenge? The Dark Lord would welcome you by his side in a heartbeat. Kill these fools and end this farce!"

Sirius cleaned his ear with his finger. "I seem to have gone spontaneously deaf," he said. "Oh dear."

"I suppose this is the point I should mention that you're entitled to legal counsel," Fiona said reluctantly. "We can wait and get a lawyer in here to represent you."

"And leave my fate in the hands of a common Muggle?" Alecto said, looking scandalized. "I think not."

Fiona pulled out a notebook and a cheap blue pen, narrating as she wrote. "The… suspect… waived… her right… to legal representation. Great, moving on.. oh, right—the charges." She leaned down to look the witch in the eye. "Treason is the only crime I'm aware of that still carries the death penalty in the United Kingdom," she said. "Traditionally, the punishment was executed—pardon the expression—by means of being dragged behind a horse, disemboweled, beheaded, and chopped into quarters. I'm unclear of the order of operations, there, but I'd personally opt to begin with the beheading."

The blood drained from Alecto's face.

"Don't worry," Fiona said. "They'd never do that to you, of course. The punishment for women, naturally, was to be burned at the stake like a witch. Pardon the expression."

To Fiona's surprise, Alecto's eyes lit up. "At the stake, you say?"

Hannah coughed. "Sorry to interrupt, Ms. Smythe, but you might want to know that we learned in History of Magic last year that you can't actually burn witches."

"Naturally not," Fiona said. "We're a civilized society, now. No judge in the land would sentence someone to burning."

"Oh, I wouldn't know anything about that," Hannah said. "I just meant that there's a simple charm from old witch hunting days to protect from just such a threat."

"No kidding?" Fiona said, her momentum totally thrown. "Wait, do you mean to tell me that the old medieval witch hunts actually caught witches? That they weren't just a bunch of angry mobs going around executing helpless women based on nothing more than suspicion, xenophobia, ageism, and sexism? That the only thing preventing them from working was that the witches were immune to fire?! That rather than 'dangerous and extra-judiciary mob justice,' the phrase 'witch-hunt' should mean 'it all would have worked except that they hadn't invented the guillotine yet?'"

"Erm, I suppose," Hannah said. "A lot of innocent Muggle women were burned under suspicion of witchcraft."

"Bet they would have appreciated a fireproof charm right around then," Fiona muttered. "Typical." She rounded on Alecto. "Don't think that you can magic your way out of this one, though," she said. "They changed the punishment to hanging, so unless you've got a Vertebrate-to-Steel Charm as well, you're clear out of luck."

This was true, though Fiona didn't mention that this hadn't been carried out since the Second World War. She doubted any modern judge would sentence someone to be hanged in this day and age, as any lawyer would have told Alecto.

"H-hanging?" Alecto quailed, confirming no such charm existed. "Barbarian! You—you have no proof!"

"Uhhhh," Fiona said sarcastically, "oh, no! Proof! I completely forgot about to get any of that—except, oh, waitaminute, the sworn testimony and contemporaneous notes of police sergeant, you ruddy idiot. Plus mountains of physical evidence you and your gang left behind back in the 80s. Unless you used a spell that erase your fingerprints each and every time you killed some hapless Muggle? What about DNA evidence—do you even know what that is? No? I didn't think so. I've got dozens of coppers lined up that are just itching to solve a few cold-case murders you committed in your stupid war."

"My friends will decorate your courthouse with the judge's entrails before it gets that far," Alecto growled, blatantly seeking refuge in sheer bluster. "You have no idea who you're dealing with, Muggle. Let me go now and I'll ensure you're awarded a quick death."

"They'd have to go through me," Milo said. "Remember what happened when you and 'your friends' tried your hands against me in the Gryffindor Common Room? Oh—unrelatedly, did I mention that I can find you anywhere you are in the world, in the work of a moment?"

Alecto looked a little shaken, but said nothing.

"For something as high-profile as a treason case, Muggle security will be out in force. I don't remember it, but I'm sure you do—you remember what happened to your brother when my colleague put a bullet in his leg? There's more where that came from."

Alecto scoffed, mustering up a bit of bravado. "We massacred your best, Muggle. We'll do it again."

Hannah coughed. "Ms. Smythe can correct me if I'm wrong, but I saw an article in the Guardian that said there was over a hundred thousand police officers in the country."

"A hundred… thousand…" Alecto croaked.

"Your voice will be hoarse and your wand arm will have carpal tunnel before you kill us all," Fiona said smugly.

"'Never Tickle a Sleeping Dragon,'" Hannah quoted sagely. "You know, I'm starting to think the school motto wasn't talking about dragons at all, but Muggles."

"Oh, Merlin," Alecto whispered dejectedly. "I'm going to be hanged."

"Weeeerrrrrrlllll," Fiona mused. "There might be an alternative."

Alecto looked up hopefully.

"See, the thing is, much as I'd love to see you go to the gallows," Fiona said, "I don't actually care one way or the other about you, per se. You're nobody. But, see, if you could provide information leading to the arrest and conviction of a person of greater importance…"

"Say, Lucius Malfoy, for example," Hannah added helpfully.

"…then I think I can persuade my comrades to look the other way, just this once, to the treason. Maybe we can stick lesser charges like conspiracy or assault."

"So I wouldn't be hanged?" Alecto asked hopefully.

"Nah. A token prison sentence and maybe some community service," Fiona said breezily.

"What do you need me to do?" Alecto asked, finally broken.

Fiona grinned wickedly.

"Have you ever heard of the Muggle phrase, 'to wear a wire?'"